DEAR X
ALL CHARACTERS, PLACES, AND EVENTS
IN THIS WORK ARE FICTITIOUS
CHILD ACTORS WERE FILMED
WITH GUARDIANS PRESENT
Wedding, you say?
I'll wipe away
all the stains from your past.
And you'll start over by my side.
What do you say?
No need to overthink it.
All you have to do
is just nod.
Then everything will get easier.
A safe, solid fence...
That's what I need.
Are you saying you can give me that?
I'll give you anything.
Can you prove what you just said?
You need proof for my words?
Say it anyway.
That if I take your hand
I'll be able to do everything I want.
Shit.
You okay?
Move!
We have to get out of here.
Are you okay?
We need to move.
I promise you, Ah-jin.
Come to me.
EPISODE 10: THE MONSTER IN THE MIRROR
Is Boss still not picking up?
I need to go.
To her place?
Yes.
This is definitely connected to her.
Yes, Mr. Hong.
I understand.
I should get going.
Grandpa's in critical condition.
Can you try to find Ah-jin?
Please.
Okay, I'll take care of it.
REST IN PEACE
THE LATE YOON SEUNG-MO
GRANDSON: YOON JUN-SEO
Gosh, I can finally digest a little.
When it's time to go
dying at the right time is
also a blessing.
Excuse me!
Here!
One bowl of stew here!
Gosh.
Jeez, you're so slow.
I got through to the boss.
It seems like nothing's wrong.
She says she'll call later.
Okay.
I'm off.
Seriously, a new bag drops
even before a whole season passes.
It's like they don't want me
to keep the ones I have.
And all I see at the department store
are the exact same bags.
Right.
They seem to be in good condition.
And most of them are
close to new, so...
So?
How much are they?
Ms. Sim Sung-hee?
- Yes?
- Hello.
Judging by that reaction,
you're definitely guilty.
You know why we're here, right?
How would I know?
Okay.
Sure.
That was Ah-jin, right?
She admitted she gave them
to me, didn't she?
Let her go.
Yes, sir.
Have a good day, guys.
Do I have to pick up calls
from the police because of you?
I was just...
I mean, you don't have a job now
so I figured
I'd sell things to help you out.
By selling my stuff?
You're a known celebrity.
It'd be embarrassing for you
to show up with these.
So, I was just helping you out.
Hey, I wasn't going to keep it all.
I was at least going to split it
50-50 with you.
You're unbelievable, Sung-hee.
If you don't like 50-50, then 60-40.
If you don't like 60-40, then 70-30!
I'm fine with only 30 percent.
Mr. Hong!
I've been waiting ages for you.
Have a drink with me.
No, ma'am. I have work to do.
What work?
It's not like the dead man will care.
Sit.
Sit down.
Do you know how long I waited?
All right.
Have a drink. Loosen up a bit.
Cheers.
You're quite the professional.
So, how was the inheritance settled?
I'm the only daughter-in-law
of this family, after all.
There was no mention of your share.
Out of all that money,
not a single piece for me?
Not even ten won?
Most of it was left
to your son, Jun-seo--
He's the grandson.
Of course, he gets something.
I'm talking about me.
How...
How could a man who doted
on his grandson, whom I raised
do this to me?
How could he?
Ma'am, legally and morally
there's no reason
you'd receive an inheritance.
Jun-seo gets it, but why not me?
I'm not asking for the same amount.
Even a quarter or a tenth!
He should have considered me
at least that much!
Strictly speaking
you and the late Chairman Yoon
are completely unrelated.
Unrelated?
Did you just call me unrelated?
Thanks for bringing that up.
Then is he his bloodline?
He's also unrelated!
Who do you think continued
this family line with no heirs?
Even if I gave birth to and raised
someone else's child
I made him a grandson worthy enough
to be in this family!
Ungrateful old man.
I should have killed him.
What did you just say?
Jun-seo!
I raised you!
Now, pay me back,
adjusted for inflation!
A hundredfold!
You made me part of this family's
bloodline for inheritance?
And you lied to me my whole life?
Yes, I did.
So what?
Why?
Why do you always live like this?
That's how everybody lives.
Those people in that funeral hall?
They're all circling for scraps
from the old man's estate.
They only pretend to be noble
on the outside.
- Mom.
- I'm not the only one who lied.
She also knew.
Baek Ah-jin, that skank, knew.
That little nine-year-old
started threatening me since then.
She drove
a wedge between us
and toyed with you.
Is that why you hit her?
You lied about me
being this family's son
and brought her
into the house for that.
It was all you.
I...
always knew...
you were a bad person.
Yet I still pitied you.
I thought, "She must be struggling.
That's why she's like that."
I tried to understand you.
I tried so hard.
And with Ah-jin,
I thought I should pay the price.
But why did you do that to me?
It was for you.
So you could live with a good father.
I didn't want you
inheriting my poverty.
So, from the very beginning
I was never
the true grandson of Grandpa
and the wounds she's carried
all her life were because of me.
Sure. Keep thinking that.
Haunted by the past forever.
Pathetic.
Hey.
Get out.
Baek Ah-jin.
You know this, right?
After I dropped out of high school,
my family collapsed.
That's when everything went
wrong for me.
So?
What's that got to do with me?
Why did you do that to me back then?
I want an apology, though it's late.
Sung-hee.
Apologies are for people
who did something wrong.
Are you not even a little sorry?
Why would I be?
You lost because you got greedy
trying to beat me.
You were clueless, stupid
and had no awareness
of your place or the situation.
And you kept poking at me.
You just got unlucky.
Happy?
Bitch.
Why are you here this late?
And where are you going this late?
I heard about your grandfather.
I was going to call later--
You won't even take my calls now.
When exactly is later?
Your mom got a kidney from you
your grandfather died
and now you come
to take it out on me?
Do I have to pick up your calls
on command?
Sorry
but I don't have the luxury
of waiting by the phone for you.
I told you to wait.
If you waited, I would come to you.
That was the one thing I asked you.
And you couldn't even do that?
You knew I was an illegitimate child
and that I had
a different biological father.
Is that true?
It's not, right?
So, you finally found out.
Now you know
why I went through all that.
How does it feel now?
Relieved?
Why did you lie to me?
Jun-seo.
I never lied to you.
I just didn't tell you.
And shouldn't you be grateful to me?
Because you were kept in the dark
you got help from your grandfather
lived in a nice home,
and wrote in peace.
If I had told you then
how different
would your life have been?
You would have run away,
hidden, or suffered
like an idiot.
So...
you're saying you did that for me?
Yes.
Can you say I'm wrong?
Everything you enjoyed
because you were Yoon Jun-seo.
Can you deny all of that?
This is why I didn't tell you.
Because you wouldn't be able
to handle it.
I would have endured.
If you hadn't lied
or hid it from me...
If you had told me
that you suffered because of me...
I would have endured
anything for you.
Somehow.
- Hello, ma'am.
Actress Baek Ah-jin
and CEO Moon Do-hyuk
have officially tied the knot,
holding a wedding ceremony
at a cathedral in Sicily.
As the marriage between a top actress
and a chaebol businessman
their union has been dubbed
the wedding of the century
drawing widespread attention.
Speculation continues about
where the newlyweds will establish...
She's out of the picture.
- What?
- Kid.
My instincts are razor sharp.
Baek Ah-jin. She's the broom, right?
Hey.
- Do you know this man?
- Of course.
Who in Korea doesn't know
Moon Do-hyuk?
He's rich, handsome, and competent.
He's perfect.
Anyway, it's over now that
she married into a chaebol family.
She achieved every woman's dream.
Just wish her well now.
Once she's with a guy like that...
even stalkers would give up.
You should let her go, too.
And the office fire turned out to be
a simple electrical short.
Why spin stories
about warnings and threats?
Sure.
I guess that's all it was.
Can you say I'm wrong?
Everything you enjoyed
because you were Yoon Jun-seo.
Can you deny all of that?
LENA
Will you be gone long?
Yes.
A very long time.
I won't come back at all if I can.
Text me if you get bored.
I won't.
I might want to come back home.
Can I give you a piece of advice?
Get away from Baek Ah-jin, too.
I'm not telling you to come to me.
But I hope that you will live
your own life now.
As human Yoon Jun-seo.
Yes.
I will.
And I'm not going to write anymore.
- I doubt it.
- I mean it.
I'm putting down writing,
and I'm letting go of Ah-jin.
I want to give myself some time.
Good choice.
You might finally start acting
like a human being.
Too bad I won't be around to see it.
Take care.
I'm leaving.
AMEN TO NOTHING
I want to look around a bit.
Can you open the door?
I'm afraid only Mr. Moon is allowed
into the third-floor study, ma'am.
Is that right?
I just want to look.
I can't even do that?
Am I not also
the master of this house?
Even the previous madam
wasn't allowed.
It's entirely
Mr. Moon's private space.
That makes me feel weird.
If she wasn't allowed,
does that mean I'm also not allowed?
I'm a little hurt, Ms. Gong.
I'm not her, you know.
If you insist
- perhaps you could speak with--
- Forget it.
The movie shoot starts
next week, right?
How do you feel?
It's the project you wanted so badly.
Not bad.
Thanks to my capable husband
I met a skilled director.
I guess I'm a little excited.
What does it feel like
to get everything you want?
Mostly boring.
Especially when it's easy.
Was I easy to get?
You know the answer.
You were someone
I invested a lot of effort into.
So, it felt the best
when I finally had you.
That's why I brought you
a major film so quickly.
Do you have any other questions?
Can I use your study
on the third floor?
The study?
Why?
It's hard to concentrate
on my script.
I want a quiet space to practice
but the house is always crowded.
The study won't magically make you
practice better, though.
I'll practice with you instead.
You will?
Yes.
Just read this section.
- Let's see.
- But
are you sure you can handle it?
What kind of character
am I supposed to play?
It would help to know
so I can match the tone.
He's the real culprit
behind the murder
of the protagonist's family.
I take revenge on him later.
A murderer, then.
Have you ever killed anyone?
- Pardon?
- Or did you have
anyone you wanted to kill?
Do-hyuk?
Did I ever tell you
why I divorced my ex-wife?
She kept saying she wanted to kill me
so I divorced her.
I gave her everything she wanted
and treated her like royalty.
Maybe that's why.
Whenever something went
slightly wrong or didn't satisfy her
she couldn't handle it.
She blamed everything on me
saying that I made her that way.
Eventually,
she had a complete breakdown.
Now she's being treated
in a psychiatric hospital.
Maybe I treated her too well,
above her place.
It broke my heart.
Did I shock you?
I went off track, didn't I?
Not really.
Ready, action!
Sister, I know
who killed your family.
It's someone you know.
- I'll go ahead and order first.
- Sure.
Have you ever killed anyone?
- Pardon?
- Or did you have
anyone you wanted to kill?
What a psycho.
They say Baek Ah-jin's husband
got her this role.
Figures. I thought it was weird
how public opinion flipped overnight
after her image collapsed like that.
Someone must have pulled strings.
Man, I wish I had
a rich husband, too.
I'd live however I want.
Seriously.
Life is so unpredictable.
Who knew she'd break up
with Heo In-gang like that
and immediately marry
into a chaebol family?
She obviously married him for money.
It won't last.
Bet they'll have
divorce rumors next year.
Hey, that was a little harsh.
Enjoy your coffee.
RIP
THE LATE YOON SEUNG-MO
Thank you.
Thank you for taking me in...
and raising me.
And I'm sorry.
I don't think I can come back.
FOR MENSTRUAL CRAMPS
Who brought this here?
You're home.
You're early today.
Yes.
How was today's shoot?
Did you do well?
Of course.
You look a bit tired.
Are you feeling unwell?
Do-hyuk.
There's something I want to ask.
Never mind. Maybe I'm just tired.
You don't seem to have a fever.
Are you sure you're okay?
It's just fatigue.
I'm fine.
All right.
Then I'll go shower.
Get some rest in the meantime.
Since when was it like this?
I apologize, ma'am.
I noticed it was broken this morning
but I forgot
because things got hectic.
I'll fix it right away.
You're just waiting
for time to pass, aren't you?
But too bad for you.
The moment you want so badly
will never come.
What happened to you?
You never call me out first.
You okay?
You look better than I expected.
I thought you'd be moping around
like some lost puppy.
This guy.
What is it?
Why did you call me?
Something's going on, right?
I called you to drink.
We're at a bar. Why else?
You're too old
for teenage turmoil now.
What about you?
I've always wondered.
How do you sacrifice your whole life
just for the sake of another person?
My life isn't worth
betting on.
I'm the delinquent son
who killed his own dad.
No family wants me
nor do I have a clue what I live for.
Who's going to complain
if I bet a life like that
on someone else?
You should start
living your own life.
So you don't end up like me,
not knowing where to go.
Idiot.
You're so fucking drunk right now.
Excuse me.
I'll handle my life.
You deal with yours.
You're the one acting pitiful.
Who's the lost puppy here?
Unbelievable.
Jun-seo.
If you don't know where to go
do you want me to show you?
Let's go for Round Two.
You're paying.
Deal?
Lady!
Lady, are you done yet?
Gosh, you're so slow.
Hurry up already.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm here.
You came.
Good.
- Ms. Baek, please say a word!
- A comment, please!
- Will there be another movie?
- About your return!
Ms. Baek Ah-jin!
- Just one comment!
- Ms. Baek Ah-jin!
Excuse me.
Long time no see.
How did you recognize me?
How could I not?
You were staring at me from there.
But what brings you here?
Nothing, well...
You just stopped contacting me
and I haven't seen you in a while.
So, I just wanted to check
if you were doing okay.
You are okay, right?
You look pale.
There's no life in your face
as if you're sick.
I'm not sure
if I'm doing okay.
It's just that I've been having
nightmares every night.
I'm just tired.
What?
Did you fall for me or something?
Stop staring.
Hey, Jae-oh.
Can you look
into Moon Do-hyuk for me?
Moon Do-hyuk?
Your husband?
I knew it.
That bastard was up to something,
wasn't he?
It's not that.
I just have a weird feeling.
Find out about his ex-wife in detail.
And where she is now.
Even better
if I can talk to her in person.
Hold on.
He had an ex-wife?
So, he's been married before?
Jeez.
I knew I hated that guy from day one.
Why are you getting mad?
Why did you marry
someone like him?
You're way out of his league.
Cut the nonsense.
- Can you do it or not?
- Don't even bother asking.
Just wait. I'll dig up everything
and won't leave a single detail out.
Ma'am, have some warm tea before bed.
I don't want any.
After that day,
Mr. Moon insisted that you drink it.
If you refuse, he'll get on my case.
Where's Ah-jin?
Such lovely weather, ma'am.
I wish every day were like this.
Right?
"I pray that every path I take
be cursed with blood."
AMEN TO NOTHING
It fucking pissed me off even more
when I thought about it.
I crawled into your house
just to watch you fall
and this is how you treat me?
My whole life is ruined
because of you.
And you...
It's not fair
you get to rise even higher
and live in this mansion.
Who said you could?
You will never get away from me!
Why you?
Why does a devil like you
get to do well?
Sung-hee.
You failed because you were stupid.
Don't blame other people.
Fine. If I can't be like you
because I'm stupid
you can become like me.
Right? That's easier, isn't it?
Dragging you down to the bottom.
You're also finished
if that pretty face gets ruined.
But Ah-jin
you know what?
Do you think your marriage is
a blessing or a curse?
Your husband...
Sung-hee.
DEAR X
Subtitles by Ho-young Yun